# Juan C. Colmenares H.

# **Electronic Engineer**

I am a PhD Candidate and my research focuses on the design, manufacturing, testing and development of power electronics systems using Silicon Carbide (SiC) for a wide variety of purposes. In particular, I have been focusing on high efficiency, high temperature design using SiC power modules for automotive and aerospace applications, respectively. I considered myself as a hard-working engineer with a strong motivation for R&D, innovation and entrepreneurship.

Address: Stockholm, Sweden Mobile: +46 72 293 9521 Office: +46 8 790 6627 Date of Birth: 4th of July, 1989 Maracaibo, Venezuela Place of Birth:

Citizenship: Venezuelan Email: iuanco@kth.se https://www.kth.se/profile/juanco/ Web Site:

**EDUCATION** 

PhD Candidate, 4th year 2012 - Present

KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Silicon Carbide(SiC) Group, at the Department of Electrical Energy Conversion, Electrical Engineering School. Stockholm, Sweden.

2010 - 2011 **Exchange Student** 

KTH Royal Institute of Technology, 60 ECTS Credits in Master Courses and Master Thesis. Stockholm, Sweden.

Electrical Engineer Degree (5 years program)

2006 - 2012 Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB), GPA 4.80/5. Sartenejas, Venezuela.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

KTH Royal Institute of Technology 2012 - 2015

Electrical Machines and Drives (EJ2200 - EJ2201) - Laboratory and Project Assistant.

Power Electronics (EJ2300 - EJ2301) - Laboratory and Teacher Assistant.

**WORK EXPERIENCE** 

SiCify AB 2014-Present

Founder. KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Start - Up. Stockholm, Sweden.

Industria Eléctrica Gallium C.A 2009

Intern. 6 weeks. Engineering Department. Manufacture, design and diagnose of voltage protectors. Caracas, Venezuela.

PECA C.A 2008

Intern. 6 weeks. Warehouse Management of industrial electrical materials, luminaries assembly, installations of voltage diesel power plants. Maracaibo, Venezuela.

**AWARDS** 

Graduated Honors "Summa Cum Laude" 2012

Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB). Sartenejas, Venezuela.

**Honorable Mention for Master Thesis** 2011

Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB), "Analysis, Implementation and Experimental Evaluation of a Phase Shifted PWM Control System for a Modular Multilevel Converter ". Sartenejas, Venezuela.

Student Unions Notable. Academic Performance Award. 2009

Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB). Sartenejas, Venezuela.

Electronic Engineering Student Union's. Academic Performance Award. 2009 Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB). Sartenejas, Venezuela.

2006 Silver medalist in Junior National Mathematics Olympiad

Maracaibo, Venezuela,

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native language.

English: Professional level

Bodwells English Summer School. Vancouver, Canada.

Salisbury English Summer School. Salisbury, United Kingdom.

Berlitz English School. Maracaibo, Venezuela.

2006

2007

2008

Swedish: Basic level

KTH Royal Institute of Technology. Stockholm, Sweden.

French: Basic level

Alianza Francesa, Caracas, Venezuela.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

#### International Journals

[1] **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Jacek Rabkowski, Diane-Perle Sadik, Georg Tolstoy, H-P. Nee, "High-Efficiency 312-kVA Three-Phase Inverter using Parallel Connection of Silicon Carbide MOSFET Power Modules," In *IEEE Transactions on Industry Applications*, 2015.

[2] **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Jacek Rabkowski, Diane-Perle Sadik, and H-P. Nee. "Dual-function gate driver for a power module with SiC junction field-effect transistors." *IEEE Transactions on Power Electronics*, vol. 29, no. 5 (2014): 2367-2379.

#### International Conferences

- [1] **Juan Colmenares**, Diane-Perle Sadik, Patrik Hilbert, H-P. Nee, "Reliability Analysis of a High-Efficiency SiC Three-Phase Inverter for Motor Drive Applications." In 31st Annual IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference & Exposition (APEC 2016).
- [2] Diane-Perle Sadik, Konstantine Kostov, **Juan Colmenares**, H-P. Nee, "Analysis of Parasitic Elements of Silicon Carbide Power Modules with Special Emphasis on Reliability Issues." In 31st Annual IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference & Exposition (APEC 2016)
- [3] Georg Tolstoy, Per Ranstad, **Juan Colmenares**, Florian Giezendanner, and Hans-Peter Nee. "Experimental evaluation of SiC BJT and SiC MOSFET in a series resonant converter." In 2015 17th European Conference on Power Electronics and Applications (EPE'15-ECCE Europe), 2015.
- [4] Georg Tolstoy, Per Ranstad, **Juan Colmenares**, Florian Giezendanner, and Hans-Peter Nee. "Dual control used in series-loaded resonant converter with SiC devices." In 2015 International Conference on Power Electronics (ICPE Seoul 2015-ECCE-ASIA), 2015.
- [5] Georg Tolstoy, Per Ranstad, **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Florian Giezendanner, Jacek Rabkowski, and H-P. Nee. "An experimental analysis on how the dead-time of SiC BJT and SiC MOSFET impacts the losses in a high-frequency resonant converter." In 2014 16th European Conference on Power Electronics and Applications (EPE'14-ECCE Europe), pp. 1-10, 2014.
- [6] **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Georg Tolstoy, Diane Sadik, H-P. Nee, and Jacek Rabkowski. "High-efficiency three-phase inverter with SiC MOSFET power modules for motor-drive applications." In 2014 IEEE Energy Conversion Congress and Exposition (ECCE), pp. 468-474, 2014.
- [7] Diane-Perle Sadik, **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Georg Tolstoy, Jacek Rabkowski, and H-P. Nee. "Analysis of short-circuit conditions for silicon carbide power transistors and suggestions for protection." In 2014 16th European Conference on Power Electronics and Applications (EPE'14-ECCE Europe), pp. 1-10, 2014.
- [8] **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, H-P. Nee, and Jacek Rabkowski. "Switching performance of parallel-connected power modules with SiC MOSFETs." In 2014 International Power Electronics Conference (IPEC Hiroshima 2014-ECCE ASIA), pp. 3712-3717, 2014.
- [9] H-P. Nee, Jacek Rabkowski, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Georg Tolstoy, **Juan Colmenares**, Diane-Perle Sadik, MietekBakowski et al. "High-Efficiency Power Conversion Using Silicon Carbide Power Electronics." In *Materials Science Forum*, vol. 778, pp. 1083-1088. 2014.
- [10] Diane-Perle Sadik, **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Jang-Kwon Lim, Jacek Rabkowski, and H-P. Nee. "Experimental investigations of static and transient current sharing of parallel-connected silicon carbide MOSFETs." In 2013 15th European Conference on Power Electronics and Applications (EPE'13 ECCE Europe), pp. 1-10, 2013.
- [11] **Juan Colmenares**, Dimosthenis Peftitsis, Jacek Rabkowski, and H-P. Nee. "Dual-function gate driver for a power module with SiC junction field transistors." In 2013 IEEE ECCE Asia Downunder (ECCE Asia), pp. 245-250, 2013.

### **SKILLS**

C/C++ Programming and Visual Basic

MatLab, Simulink and Lab VIEW

Advanced
P-Spice, LT - Spice and PLECS

Advanced
Altium, Target and EAGLE

Autocad 2D

Basic

Microsoft Office and Latex

Advanced

Advanced

## OTHER ACTIVITIES

Karate, Brown Belt (1st KYU)	1994 - 2006
Training Course for Youth to establish enterprises. Igez y UNIMET, Maracaraibo, Venezuela.	2006
Sales Course. Maracaibo.	2006
FSAE Team. Electronic Division Member. Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB). Sartenejas, Venezuela.	2009 - 2010

## **REFERENCES**

#### Hans-Peter Nee, Professor.

Address: KTH Royal Institute of Technology. School of Electrical Engineering,

Teknikringen 33, Floor 3, Room 3326. SE-100 44. Stockholm, Sweden.

E-mail: hansi@kth.se

Phone: +46-8-790 7781. Cellular: +46-70-6953470. Fax: +46-8-20 52 68.

#### Karl Mäler, Professor.

Address: Gotlandsgatan 70A, 116 65. Stockholm, Sweden.

E-mail: karl@beijer.kva.se / karl.maler@comhem.se Phone: +46-8-641 5821. Cellular: +46-70-6681364.

#### Jose Restrepo, Professor.

Address: Universidad Simón Bolívar (USB). Sartenejas, Venezuela.

E-mail: restrepo@usb.ve

Phone: +58-2129064005 -Ext. 232.